#### AMANDA STERN

## Software Engineer

amanda.stern.73@gmail.com // cell: 607 379 9173 // Boston, MA // GitHub // LinkedIn

I have a diverse professional background as a Federal Park Ranger with experience in database management and as an Air Force Captain with Project Management experience for Software Development Testing & Fielding efforts. I am committed to utilizing best-practices in developing applications and in mastering programming languages, and am committed to utilizing best practices as a professional Software Engineer and bring an open mind and passion for learning. I bring my passion, empathy, creativity and communication skills.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, EJS, HTML,-CSS, Terminal, GitHub/Git, MongoDB, Mongoose, team leadership, logistics management, risk management, project management, software development & testing, public speaking

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineering Immersive Fellow, General Assembly, NYC, NY, Aug 2022 - Present

- Developed projects that use CSS, JavaScript, React, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, and Azure
- Projects and descriptions found on GitHub

# Bureau of Land Management Park Ranger, Miles City Field Office, MT, April 2021 – Nov 2021

- Performed field work in wilderness areas for recreation & wildland fire programs, educated public
- Assessed/mitigated risk & dispatched 12+ drivers & 15+ vehicles in wildland firefighting
- Maintained fleet vehicles & patrolled/maintained Wilderness Study Areas, dispersed recreation sites
- Utilized GIS Software, Arc Pro Databases, SQL, to plot data & create maps using ArcGIS Pro

### Bureau of Land Management Park Ranger, Little Snake Field Office, CO, June 2020 - Nov 2020

- Utilized Trimble GPS & GIS Software to plot data & create maps using ArcGIS
- Educated public on Leave No Trace ethics, general information, navigation
- Assessed/mitigated risk & dispatched 20+ personnel, 25+ vehicles & supplies in wildland firefighting
- Coordinated efforts between Logistics, Supply & Ground Support on Incident Command Post (ICP)

# United States Air Force Acquisitions Officer, Active Duty Sept 2012 – Sept 2018 Captain, Global Positioning Systems Project Manager & Test/Fielding Team Lead, May 2016-Oct 2018

- Managed integrated product team in planning & execution of formal qualification testing for satellite software command/control program
- Facilitated communication as Government liaison to Lockheed Martin, Air Force Operational Test & Evaluation Center & Sandia National Laboratories
- Briefed senior executives on development status, risk/opportunity management, program management reviews and design reviews
- Collaborated with stakeholders for schedule development & test asset/resource sharing
- Reviewed contract proposals, supported team contract negotiations & awards, oversaw contract modifications

# Lieutenant, Communication/Navigation/Surveillance for Air Traffic Management Project Manager, Sept 2012-May 2016

- Managed 8-person engineering team to review technical specifications & requirements for military compliance with Federal Aviation Administration standards
- Authored justification/analyses to award sole-source contracts for military-specific cockpit software & hardware applications
- Managed engineering team to develop software for automating flight strip printing at Air Bases in Korea
- Reviewed contract proposals, conducted contract negotiations & contract awards
- Coordinated with legal, finance, contracting teams to ensure program compliance with Federal Acquisition Regulations

### **EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS**

### General Assembly, 12-week Software Engineering Immersive

Developed Projects utilizing HTML, CSS, Javascript, Mongoose, MongoDB, Azure, React, Python

Bachelor of Science - Animal Science & Communications (double major), Cornell University, NY 2008-2012

**Federal Park Ranger Red Card Certifications:** Equipment Manager(Q), Expanded Dispatch Recorder(T), Driver(Q) for wildland fire

National Registry Emergency Medical Technician & Wilderness Emergency Medical Technician, NOLS Wilderness Medicine, Lander, Wyoming, current license through March 2023

# National Outdoor Leadership School Wilderness and Medicine Rescue Semester, Sept-Dec 2018

- 90-day leadership wilderness expedition through Utah Canyons, Wyoming backcountry
- High Angle Rock Rescue, Avalanche Level 1, Leave No Trace Master Educator